<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Symbiophore</name>
	<author>cem</author>
	<packageId>cem.symbiophore</packageId>
	<description>[b]Symbiophore: Jungle-Born Psychic Companion and Silk Producer[/b]

The Symbiophore is a fascinating, caterpillar-like creature from the dense jungles, known for its rare psychic abilities and unique silk production. These creatures are not only loyal and affectionate pets but also provide invaluable support to your psycasters. They resonate with the psychic energy around them, helping to relieve neural strain while also improving the well-being of nearby colonists.

Symbiophores serve as:
[list]
[*][b]Psychic Emanators[/b]: They enhance the mood of those nearby by emitting calming psychic emanations, provided they are well-cared for and comfortable. A content Symbiophore has a much stronger psychic effect.
[*][b]Neural Heat Sponges[/b]: Twice per day, they can absorb excess psychic entropy (neural heat) from psycasters, reducing the risk of neural overload.
[*][b]Silk Producers[/b]: Symbiophores produce [i]silk noil[/i], a raw material that can be spun into silk thread at crafting stations. In future updates, more specialized processing methods will be introduced: lucette fork and crafting spot, spinning wheel, silk reeler (industrial technology). For now, Symbiophores directly produce silk.
[*][b]Improved Combatants[/b]: Though not primarily combat animals, Symbiophores now possess a unique "gullet ejection" attack, which causes acid burn damage. This powerful ability is used defensively and can only be unleashed once per quadrum, requiring a recovery phase afterward.
[/list]

[b]Acquiring a Symbiophore[/b]:
[list]
[*][b]Animal Traders[/b]: Occasionally available from exotic and uncommon animal traders.
[*][b]Tame in the Wild[/b]: Seek them out in jungle biomes to tame these rare creatures.
[*][b]Unexpected Arrival[/b]: On rare occasions, a lost Symbiophore may wander into your colony, seeking a new home.
[/list]

Symbiophores thrive in warm, humid environments and prefer a diverse diet. They are particularly sensitive to cold and will become unhappy if exposed to low temperatures, go hungry or want for sleep. With proper care, they can even be brought into combat, but mind the ambient temperature to keep them comfortable.

[b]Current Status and Future Updates[/b]:
Symbiophores are still being balanced, and additional features or abilities may be added in future updates. The silk production system will evolve, including the introduction of specialized workstations for processing silk noil into silk thread.

---

[b]What's New?[/b]:
[list]
[*]Totally new artwork for the Symbiophore.
[*]Introduction of silk production, a valuable new resource.
[*]Psychic emanations are now more effective when the Symbiophore is comfortable and happy.
[*]Symbiophores can now participate in combat with the powerful "gullet ejection" acid attack.
[/list]

[b]Support the Mod[/b]: [url=https://ko-fi.com/N4N4NFFPZ]Support via Ko-fi[/url]

Art by Poulpe Voulant.</description>
<url>https://github.com/cemacmillan/Symbiophore</url>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.4</li>
		<li>1.5</li>
	</supportedVersions>
</ModMetaData>

